hey guys welcome to this first video in
嗨 伙计们 欢迎收看这首视频
a series of tutorials teaching how to
一系列教程讲授如何
use kdenlive so kdenlive has been my
使用Kdenlive所以Kdenlive一直是我的
go-to video editor for a long time now I
很长一段时间的视频编辑 现在我
really love this software it's really
我真的很喜欢这个软件 真的
fairly simple to use and it's very
使用起来相当简单 而且非常
powerful professional software and I
强大的专业软件和我
would say it's pretty stable and
会说它很稳定
reliable I've used it under Linux for
可靠 我已经在Linux下使用它
the most part and I'm just now starting
大部分时间 我才刚刚开始
to use it in Windows so I'm running
在Windows中使用它 这样我就可以运行
Windows 10 right now and I'm just want
现在是Windows 10 我只是想
to demonstrate this software so if you
来演示这个软件 所以如果您
haven't downloaded it yet go ahead and
还没有下载 请继续
you can check out my other video it's in
你可以看看我的另一个视频
the description of this video it'll show
它将显示这段视频的描述
you how to download and get started on
如何下载和入门
Windows if you're using this on Linux
Windows 如果您在Linux上使用此程序
awesome good for you and yeah follow
太棒了 对你很好 关注一下吧
along the interface is the same whether
界面沿线是否相同
you're on Linux Windows or Mac so yeah
您使用的是Linux、Windows或Mac 所以是的
let's dive into just getting familiar
让我们来深入了解一下
with the interface first of all so at
首先 界面是这样的
the bottom here we have our timeline we
下面我们有我们的时间表 我们
see we have video three two one audio
你看 我们有视频321音频
one and two these are our different
一和二这些是我们的不同之处
tracks to the right we have a black
右手边有一辆黑色的
screen this is our project monitor where
屏幕这是我们的项目监控器
we can view
我们可以查看
well actually it's we can do project
嗯 实际上我们可以做项目
monitor or our clip monitor so we can
监视器或我们的剪辑监视器 因此我们可以
view clips that we want to add into our
查看要添加到我们的
project and then we can actually view
项目 然后我们就可以实际查看
the audio and video of our project and
我们项目的音频和视频以及
see what it look like with transitions
看看过渡是什么样子的
or effects applied and things like that
或应用效果之类的东西
right here is the different options this
下面是不同的选项
panel in the middle and all these panels
中间的面板和所有这些面板
can be moved around by the way we can
可以通过我们可以移动的方式
move them and have them be up here
把他们搬过来 让他们上来
somewhere else so that they don't have
其他地方 这样他们就不会有
to stay right there we can drag and drop
要停留在那里 我们可以拖放
and configure it to wherever we would
并将其配置到我们想要的任何位置
like but this is just the default layout
类似 但这只是默认布局
so this section is our options for doing
因此 这一部分是我们的选项
different kinds of effects we've got all
不同种类的效果 我们都有
these different audio effects and video
这些不同的音频效果和视频
effects and filters that we can apply
我们可以应用的效果和滤镜
and we can just search for a certain one
我们可以只搜索某个特定的
if we want to do like a fade we can type
如果我们想要像淡入淡出一样 我们可以打字
in fade and it'll show us all the
在褪色中 它将向我们展示所有
different fade options we have and then
我们有不同的淡入淡出选项 然后
over here on the left hand side is our
在这里的左侧是我们的
project bin so this is where we will put
Project Bin 这就是我们要放的地方
all of our projects all of the data we
我们所有的项目所有的数据我们
want to bring in so if we want to bring
想要带来 所以如果我们想带来
in one for example right now we could
例如 现在我们可以
just go to project add clip and then we
只需转到项目添加剪辑 然后我们
find it will bring up a dial
找到它会调出一个刻度盘
and I just go to that place on my
我只是坐着我的车去那个地方
computer where I want to add in so maybe
我想要添加的计算机 所以也许
I'll do this
我会这么做的
TJ intro and go open so this is the
TJ介绍 然后打开 这是
intro screen for my video I'll hit play
我的视频的介绍屏幕 我将点击播放
and sometimes this is kind of a glitch
有时这是一种小故障
this is only happening to me in Windows
这只在Windows中发生在我身上
but I hit play and nothing happens I
但我按了播放 什么也没发生
have to give it a little jumpstart and
必须给它一点动力 然后
left click in the timeline and then
在时间线中左键单击 然后
it'll go so that'll be fixed you know
会好的 这样就能修好了 你知道的
probably by the time you're watching
很可能在你收看的时候
this that glitch won't be here anymore
这个小故障不会再存在了
but at least it's happening to me on
但至少这件事发生在我身上
Windows right now so if I could hit play
Windows现在 所以如果我可以点击Play
nothing happens I click the timeline and
什么都没发生我点击时间线
it'll start playing so we can see this
它将开始播放 这样我们就可以看到这个
video here it's in my project so it's
视频在这里 它在我的项目中 所以
not yet in my timeline to get it down to
在我的时间线上还没有把它降到
the timeline I have to left-click and
我必须左键点击的时间线
drag it down to either one of one of
将其拖到以下任一位置
these three tracks so the very lowermost
这三个音轨是最低的
track is where I usually put it on video
曲目是我通常把它放在视频上的地方
1 and now we can come play it here on
现在我们可以在这里播放它了
our project and see what it looks like
我们的项目 看看它是什么样子
awesome
太棒了
that's pretty cool we can scroll here we
这很酷 我们可以在这里滚动
can scroll through we can use our scroll
可以滚动 我们可以使用我们的滚动
wheel to kind of go to a different point
方向盘转到一个不同的点
in the video this is on our project
在视频中 这是我们的项目
monitor again and if we come down to the
再次监视 如果我们深入到
timeline we can also click on the
时间表我们也可以点击
timeline and see this is really small if
时间线 看到这真的很小 如果
I want to make this appear larger I can
我想让它看起来更大一点 我可以
kind of zoom in so I can go down here to
放大一些 这样我就可以到这里来
the bottom right hand I can zoom and
右下角我可以缩放和
make this kind of film or of this space
制作这样的电影或这个空间
and at the top it shows the seconds so
在顶部显示秒数 所以
this is point two seconds this is wait
这是点2秒 这是等待
what is that or 1 this is 1.2 seconds
这是多少还是1这是1.2秒
right here this is 2 it's about a
就在这里 这是2 这是关于一个
two-second clip it says the seconds
两秒剪辑它说的是秒
across the top we can also get a video
在顶部 我们还可以看到一段视频
and audio into our project by just
和音频输入我们的项目 只需
dragging and dropping so if you open up
拖放 所以如果你打开
a window I'll go to Maya downloads
我将转到Maya下载的一个窗口
folder actually I'll go to my music
文件夹实际上我要去听我的音乐了
first I have an audio file
首先 我有一个音频文件
I'll left-click and drag and drag it up
我将左键单击并将其拖到上方
here you always have to put it into your
在这里 你总是要把它放进你的
projects your project bin at first you
投射你的项目垃圾箱首先是你
can't just drag it down into your
不能就这么把它拖到你的
timeline it won't work you have to first
时间表它不会起作用的你必须先
bring it in and Katyn life supports many
把它带进来 卡廷的生活支撑着许多人
audio and video formats in fact I don't
音频和视频格式 事实上我不知道
think I've ever ran into trouble unless
我想我曾经遇到过麻烦 除非
you try and drag in something like well
你试着把井之类的东西拖进来
you can even drag in a picture so that's
你甚至可以拖入一张图片 这样就可以
just a still shot a still image we can
只是一张静态照片 一张我们能拍到的静止图像
drag that in but if we try to drag in
把它拖进来 但如果我们试图拖进来
something that it doesn't
一些它不会做的事情
or what I'm trying to think real quick
或者我正在试着快速思考的事情
like this Inkscape shortcut my goodness
像这样的Inkscape快捷方式我的天哪
it even lets us do that but some files
它甚至允许我们这样做 但有些文件
it doesn't let us do so just be aware of
它不会让我们这样做 只要意识到
that if it's like a non video a non
如果它像非视频一样 那就不是
media format for example like this one
媒体格式 例如这样的格式
let's do that I want to try to get an
我们就这么做吧 我想试着得到一个
error message here it's just not letting
这里的错误信息就是不让
us do it let's go back here to downloads
我们做吧 让我们回到这里的下载
and I can drag in I have this cyclist
我可以拉进来 我有一个骑自行车的人
video will drag in here and so oh it did
视频将拖到这里 哦 它做到了
bring us an error message there we go it
给我们带来一条错误消息 我们开始吧
says inks Oh perfect so yeah it wouldn't
说墨水 哦完美 所以它不会
let us if you try and drag something in
如果你想把什么东西拖进去 让我们
in that it doesn't support it'll just
因为它不支持它 只是
come up with an error message and that's
提出一个错误消息 那就是
what I was doing there it's saying we
我在那里做的是在说我们
can't do it
我做不到
alright dragging the cyclists footage
好的 拖着自行车手的镜头
and now I can I come toggle through and
现在我可以我来切换和
look at all these I can look at this
看看所有这些 我可以看看这个
picture look at this this is a vector
看这张图 这是一个矢量
graphics image which is supported also
也受支持的图形图像
so if I want to have this picture I just
所以如果我想要这张照片 我只是
drag it down to the timeline I can put
把它拖到我可以放的时间线上
it in here after a video one or I can
它在这里拍了一段视频后我可以
bring it up and have it be separate and
把它拿出来 让它分开 然后
it's just gonna play this steel image
它只会播放这个钢铁形象
for a little while it's gonna keep
在一小段时间内 它将保持
playing it we can go along this timeline
播放它 我们可以沿着这个时间线前进
if I double click it'll tell me it's
如果我双击它 它会告诉我
playing for duration five seconds but I
玩了五秒钟 但我
can change this down to two seconds and
可以将其更改为两秒 然后
hit OK and now it's only gonna play for
点击OK 现在它只会播放
two seconds so it'll play this little
两秒钟 这样它就会播放这个小
video intro and then we'll also play
视频介绍 然后我们还将播放
this video for two seconds this steel
这个视频两秒钟就是这个钢材
shot here and if you want to add audio
在此拍摄 如果您想添加音频
to this we can just drag this audio file
为此 我们只需拖动此音频文件即可
that I brought in we'll put it down here
我带进来的 我们把它放在这里
and see what this sounds like
看看这听起来像什么
[Music]
[音乐]
so then we have that audio file along
然后我们就有了音频文件
with this video footage so now we have
有了这段视频片段 现在我们有
all three of these and if we overlap
所有这三个 如果我们重叠
this we can actually overlap and
这是我们实际上可以重叠的
whatever the higher number track is
无论编号较高的轨道是什么
that's what will be be displayed first
这就是首先要展示的内容
so as soon as it gets to this video
所以一旦它到达这段视频
it'll start playing this next one after
它将在之后开始播放下一首
that we're not gonna play any effects
我们不会发挥任何影响
right now because I'm actually going to
现在因为我真的要
stop this video and we'll move on to the
停止这段视频 我们将继续
next tutorial where we will get into
下一个教程 我们将进入
doing some of these effects but I just
做一些这样的效果 但我只是
wanted to show roughly I kind of wanted
想粗略地展示一下我想要的
to show the interface and what you can
显示界面以及您可以执行的操作
do oh and one more thing will you'll
哦 还有一件事你会做的
want to do is go into your project
想要做的就是投入到你的项目中
settings so we go to project where's
设置 因此我们转到项目Where‘s
that at
那是在
when you first open it you'll it should
当你第一次打开它的时候 它应该是
bring up and say what kind of things do
提出并说出什么样的事情会做
you want to do well here this project
你想在这里做好这个项目
settings under project so the project
项目下的设置 以便项目
settings is where you'll decide if
设置是您决定是否
you're doing 1080p video and what
你在做1080p的视频什么的
framerate you're doing it at 29.97 so
帧速率你的速度是29.97 所以
what I have mine set at you can do for
我把我的目标定在你能做的事上
you can add a 4k video we can have our
您可以添加一段4k视频 我们可以
project be set up for just like 720 so
项目设置为720左右
if you're not familiar with these you'll
如果您对这些不熟悉 您将
want to learn and make sure that you're
想要学习并确保你是
editing in the right kind of thing I
在正确的事情上编辑我
usually do 1080p 30fps roughly for my
我的视频通常是1080p 30fps
YouTube videos and this is the software
YouTube视频和这个软件
that I'll use to edit all my YouTube
我会用来编辑我所有的YouTube
videos and upload them and then you have
视频并上传它们 然后你有
some different options up here too or we
在这里也有不同的选择
can create a new project we can save our
我们可以创建一个新的项目
project undo and redo and then we can
项目撤消和重做 然后我们可以
actually render out when we're ready and
当我们准备好的时候
we can save our video that's all I want
我们可以保存我们的视频这就是我想要的
to show for this I don't want to get too
为了证明我也不想得到
deep too quickly hopefully you've
太快了 希望你
enjoyed this video and I'll catch on the
我很喜欢这个视频 我会赶上的
next one where we'll dive deeper into
下一个我们将深入探讨
using the timeline and cutting video
使用时间轴和剪切视频
splitting and merging video together
分割和合并视频在一起
catch you on the next video
在下一个视频中看到你